<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ggplot2 on Rebecca Barter</title>
    <link>/categories/ggplot2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ggplot2 on Rebecca Barter</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 23:13:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/ggplot2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>5 useful R tips from rstudio::conf(2020) - tidy eval, piping, conflicts, bar charts and colors</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-02-05_rstudio_conf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 23:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-02-05_rstudio_conf/</guid>
      <description>Tip 1: Tidy evaluation Tip 2: Pipe into later arguments of a function using . Tip 3: Function conflicts workaround (no more dplyr::select()) Tip 4: geom_col(): you’ll never have to specify “stat = identity” for your bar plots ever again! Tip 5: Using show_col() for viewing colour palettes   This was my second year attending rstudio::conf() as a diversity scholar (and my first time as a speaker), and I was yet again blown away by the friendliness of the community and the quality of the talks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transitioning into the tidyverse (part 1)</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-08-05_base_r_to_tidyverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 22:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-08-05_base_r_to_tidyverse/</guid>
      <description>Entering the tidyverse Piping: %&amp;gt;% Data manipulation: dplyr select: select columns filter: filter to rows that satisfy certain conditions mutate: add a new variable arrange: arrange the rows of the data frame in order a variable group_by: apply other dplyr functions separately within within a group defined by one or more variables summarise/summarize: define a variable that is a summary of other variables More dplyr functions  Visualization: ggplot2 Adding geom layers More aesthetic mappings based on variables Other types of layers Histograms Boxplots Faceting  Customizing ggplot2    Most people who learned R before the tidyverse have likely started to feel a nibble of pressure to get aboard the tidyverse train.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>