<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dplyr on Rebecca Barter</title>
    <link>/categories/dplyr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dplyr on Rebecca Barter</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 23:13:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/dplyr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Across (dplyr 1.0.0): applying dplyr functions simultaneously across multiple columns</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-07-09-across/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 23:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-07-09-across/</guid>
      <description>Select helpers: selecting columns to apply the function to Using in-line functions with across A mutate example A select example   I often find that I want to use a dplyr function on multiple columns at once. For instance, perhaps I want to scale all of the numeric variables at once using a mutate function, or I want to provide the same summary for three of my variables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transitioning into the tidyverse (part 1)</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-08-05_base_r_to_tidyverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 22:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-08-05_base_r_to_tidyverse/</guid>
      <description>Entering the tidyverse Piping: %&amp;gt;% Data manipulation: dplyr select: select columns filter: filter to rows that satisfy certain conditions mutate: add a new variable arrange: arrange the rows of the data frame in order a variable group_by: apply other dplyr functions separately within within a group defined by one or more variables summarise/summarize: define a variable that is a summary of other variables More dplyr functions  Visualization: ggplot2 Adding geom layers More aesthetic mappings based on variables Other types of layers Histograms Boxplots Faceting  Customizing ggplot2    Most people who learned R before the tidyverse have likely started to feel a nibble of pressure to get aboard the tidyverse train.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mutate_all(), select_if(), summarise_at()... what&#39;s the deal with scoped verbs?!</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-01-23_scoped-verbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 23:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-01-23_scoped-verbs/</guid>
      <description>A quick useful aside: Using shorthand for functions The _if() scoped variant: perform an operation on variables that satisfy a logical criteria  select_if() rename_if() mutate_if() summarise_if()  The _at() scoped variant: perform an operation only on variables specified by name  Select helpers rename_at() mutate_at() summarise_at()  The _all() scoped variant: perform an operation on all variables at once  rename_all() mutate_all() summarise_all()  Conclusion   Note: Scoped verbs have now essentially been superseded by accross() (soon to be available in dplyr 1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>