<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Statistics on Rebecca Barter</title>
    <link>/categories/statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Statistics on Rebecca Barter</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 23:13:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s time for statistics departments to start supporting their applied students</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-07-30-applied-statistics-universities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 23:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-07-30-applied-statistics-universities/</guid>
      <description>I graduated with a PhD from UC Berkeley’s statistics department in December. My PhD dissertation consisted of three 100% applied projects (one of which was a piece of open-source software). This is, unfortunately, incredibly rare.
Over the past few years, I’ve had a number of current and prospective statistics PhD students both at Berkeley and outside Berkeley get in touch with me to ask me how I made my way through a statistics PhD by working only on applied projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which hypothesis test should I use? A flowchart</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-12-04_hypothesis_testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 23:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-12-04_hypothesis_testing/</guid>
      <description>Many years ago I taught a stats class for which one of the topics was hypothesis testing. Many of the students had a hard time remembering what situation each test was designed for, so I made a flowchart to help piece together the wild world of hypothesis tests.
While the flowchart isn’t pretty (if I made it today, it would be much more attractive), I feel like it might be useful for others, so here it is:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Instrumental Variables</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-05-23-instrumental_variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-05-23-instrumental_variables/</guid>
      <description>Suppose, as many do, that we want to estimate the effect of an action (or treatment) on an outcome. As an example, we might be interested in estimating the effect of receiving a drug vs not receiving a drug on the incidence of heart disease. In an ideal futuristic world, we would take each individual in our population and split them into two identical humans: one who receives the treatment and the other who doesn’t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The intuition behind inverse probability weighting in causal inference</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-07-05-ip-weighting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-07-05-ip-weighting/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post, I introduced causal inference as a field interested in estimating the unobservable causal effects of a treatment: i.e. the difference between some measured outcome when the individual is assigned a treatment and the same outcome when the individual is not assigned the treatment.
If you’d like to quickly brush up on your causal inference, the fundamental issue associated with making causal inferences, and in particular, the troubles that arise in the presence of confounding, I suggest you read my previous post on this topic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confounding in causal inference: what is it, and what to do about it?</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-07-05-confounding/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 21:12:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-07-05-confounding/</guid>
      <description>Often in science we want to be able to quantify the effect of an action on some outcome. For example, perhaps we are interested in estimating the effect of a drug on blood pressure. While it is easy to show whether or not taking the drug is associated with an increase in blood pressure, it is surprisingly difficult to show that taking the drug actually caused an increase (or decrease) in blood pressure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ANOVA</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-02-17-anova/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-02-17-anova/</guid>
      <description>Last week, practical statistics met to discuss all things ANOVA. Below you will find the slides from my talk, but read on if you would like to learn all about ANOVA.
   When ANOVA is used and who uses it? ANOVA is used far and wide by the scientific community and beyond. Unfortunately, scientists also frequently misuse ANOVA. A study by Wu et al. (2011) showed that from a survey of 10 leading Chinese medical journals in 2008, 446 articles used ANOVA, and of those articles, 59% of them used ANOVA incorrectly.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>