<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
&lt;?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Rebecca Barter</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Rebecca Barter</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 21:13:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Instrumental Variables</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-05-23-instrumental_variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-05-23-instrumental_variables/</guid>
      <description>Suppose, as many do, that we want to estimate the effect of an action (or treatment) on an outcome. As an example, we might be interested in estimating the effect of receiving a drug vs not receiving a drug on the incidence of heart disease. In an ideal futuristic world, we would take each individual in our population and split them into two identical humans: one who receives the treatment and the other who doesn’t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ggplot2: Mastering the basics</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-11-17-ggplot2_tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 22:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-11-17-ggplot2_tutorial/</guid>
      <description>An interactive Jupyter Notebook version of this tutorial can be found at https://github.com/rlbarter/ggplot2-thw. Feel free to download it and use for your own learning or teaching adventures!
Useful resources for learning ggplot2  ggplot2 book (https://www.amazon.com/dp/0387981403/ref=cm_sw_su_dp?tag=ggplot2-20) by Hadley Wickham The layered grammar of graphics (http://vita.had.co.nz/papers/layered-grammar.pdf) by Hadley Wickham   Materials outline I will begin by providing an overview of the layered grammar of graphics upon which ggplot2 is built. I will then teach ggplot2 by layering examples on top of one another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A basic tutorial of caret: the machine learning package in R</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-11-17-caret_tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-11-17-caret_tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Materials prepared by Rebecca Barter. Package developed by Max Kuhn.
An interactive Jupyter Notebook version of this tutorial can be found at https://github.com/rlbarter/STAT-215A-Fall-2017/tree/master/week11. Feel free to download it and use for your own learning or teaching adventures!
R has a wide number of packages for machine learning (ML), which is great, but also quite frustrating since each package was designed independently and has very different syntax, inputs and outputs.
This means that if you want to do machine learning in R, you have to learn a large number of separate methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Basic Data Science Workflow</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-08-16-data-science-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-08-16-data-science-workflow/</guid>
      <description>Developing a seamless, clean workflow for data analysis is harder than it sounds, especially because this is something that is almost never explicitly taught. Apparently we are all just supposed to “figure it out for ourselves”. For most of us, when we start our first few analysis projects, we basically have no idea how we are going to structure all of our files, or even what files we will need to make.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The intuition behind inverse probability weighting in causal inference</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-07-05-ip-weighting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-07-05-ip-weighting/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post, I introduced causal inference as a field interested in estimating the unobservable causal effects of a treatment: i.e. the difference between some measured outcome when the individual is assigned a treatment and the same outcome when the individual is not assigned the treatment.
If you’d like to quickly brush up on your causal inference, the fundamental issue associated with making causal inferences, and in particular, the troubles that arise in the presence of confounding, I suggest you read my previous post on this topic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confounding in causal inference: what is it, and what to do about it?</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-07-05-confounding/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 21:12:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-07-05-confounding/</guid>
      <description>Often in science we want to be able to quantify the effect of an action on some outcome. For example, perhaps we are interested in estimating the effect of a drug on blood pressure. While it is easy to show whether or not taking the drug is associated with an increase in blood pressure, it is surprisingly difficult to show that taking the drug actually caused an increase (or decrease) in blood pressure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating from GitHub Pages to Netlify: how and why?</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-06-29-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-06-29-website/</guid>
      <description>Goodbye GitHub Pages, I hope you’re not too upset! After finding myself increasingly frustrated with GitHub Pages inability to cooperate with my website engine of choice, Hugo, I’ve decided to make a move. Here are the reasons why:
Having all of my project pages being subpages of my personal page felt weird.
 Dealing with git subtrees, merge conflicts on the master branch, and having to do all kinds of work-arounds to get Hugo to play nice with GitHub Pages was driving me crazy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coolors: choosing color schemes</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-06-27-colors/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-06-27-colors/</guid>
      <description>Choosing a color palette for a visualization can be one of the most time consuming parts for perfectionists like me. It can be surprisingly difficult to decide on a palette that is both visually appealing and practical, but fortunately there do exist websites to help!
For example, Coolors shoots random, appealing, color palettes at you and you can swipe from one to the next with a hit of a space-bar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive visualization in R</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-04-20-interactive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-04-20-interactive/</guid>
      <description>Last week I gave an SGSA seminar on interactive visualizations in R.
Here is a long-form version of the talk.
Why be interactive? Interactivity allows the viewer to engage with your data in ways impossible by static graphs. With an interactive plot, the viewer can zoom into the areas the care about, highlight the data points that are relevant to them and hide the information that isn’t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docathon: A Week of Doumentation</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-03-7-docathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-03-7-docathon/</guid>
      <description>This week is the Docathon at BIDS (a.k.a. that wonderful place that I spend all my time).
A docathon is like a hackathon but is focused on developing material and tools for documentation. We have loads of projects signed up to receive some documentation-love and an impressive number of excited participants!
We kicked off the event with a series of tutorials for writing “good” documentation. I gave an R-specific tutorial where I discussed using devtools to both develop and document your package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ANOVA</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-02-17-anova/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-02-17-anova/</guid>
      <description>Last week, practical statistics met to discuss all things ANOVA. Below you will find the slides from my talk, but read on if you would like to learn all about ANOVA.
   When ANOVA is used and who uses it? ANOVA is used far and wide by the scientific community and beyond. Unfortunately, scientists also frequently misuse ANOVA. A study by Wu et al. (2011) showed that from a survey of 10 leading Chinese medical journals in 2008, 446 articles used ANOVA, and of those articles, 59% of them used ANOVA incorrectly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>superheat 0.1.0</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-02-05-superheat-cran/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 09:44:30 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-02-05-superheat-cran/</guid>
      <description>superheat 0.1.0 is now available on CRAN. Superheat makes it easy to create extendable, cutomizable, and most importantly, beautiful heatmaps. It has increased flexibility and user-friendliness when compared to alternatives such as heatmap() and pheatmap().
For usage options see the vignette and for examples see the accompanying paper by Barter and Yu (2017).
You can install the latest version with:
install.packages(&amp;quot;superheat&amp;quot;) Stay tuned for new versions with added features and minor usability tweaks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Present Good</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-02-02-how-to-present-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 09:44:30 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-02-02-how-to-present-good/</guid>
      <description>This week I was asked to give a presentation on giving presentations.
So meta.
Anyway, my lack of desire to spend time writing something that may have already been written by someone else led me to find a number of existing slides written by others with the same goal: to present on presenting. The only problem was that although these slides all contained excellent tips on making and subsequently presenting talks, the slides themselves were perfect examples of what not to do when making slides; they were insurmountable walls of text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Superheat: a simple example</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-02-02-superheat-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 09:44:30 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-02-02-superheat-example/</guid>
      <description>Making beautiful and customizable heatmaps just got way easier… Introducing the superheat R package!
Using superheat, it is now extremely easy to produce plots like the example below describing 10 randomly selected cars from the famous mtcars dataset.
library(superheat) set.seed(1347983) selected.rows &amp;lt;- sample(1:nrow(mtcars), 10) X.col &amp;lt;- matrix(&amp;quot;black&amp;quot;, ncol = ncol(mtcars), nrow = 10) X.col[scale(mtcars[selected.rows, ]) &amp;lt; 0] &amp;lt;- &amp;quot;white&amp;quot; superheat(mtcars[selected.rows,], # add text X.text = round(as.matrix(mtcars[selected.rows, ])), X.text.col = X.col, # scale columns scale = T, # label aesthetics left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gender Issues Roundtable Discussion: A Case Study in Uncomfortable Conversations</title>
      <link>/blog/2016-12-15-gender-bias/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 21:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016-12-15-gender-bias/</guid>
      <description>by Kellie Ottoboni, Rebecca Barter, Ryan Giordano, Sara Stoudt
In 2015, UC Berkeley experienced a series of high-profile sexual harassment incidents, prompting the graduate students in the Statistics Department to hold a roundtable event. While this response was initiated by overt sexual harassment, our discussion extended to other subtler gender biases. This article outlines the events that lead to the roundtable’s inception, the details of organizing and hosting the event, and our thoughts on what did and didn’t work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The only reason one should ever use a pie chart</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-07-23-pie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 21:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-07-23-pie/</guid>
      <description>Pie charts are terrible Pie charts are notoriously terrible for data visualization. Humans are genuinely bad at comparing angles. Thus, the only reason one should ever use a pie chart is to make beautiful pie-chart-art.
par(mar = c(0, 1, 0, 1)) pie( c(280, 60, 20), c(&amp;#39;Sky&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Sunny side of pyramid&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Shady side of pyramid&amp;#39;), col = c(&amp;#39;#0292D8&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;#F7EA39&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;#C4B632&amp;#39;), init.angle = -50, border = NA )  Figure 1: Pyramid pie chart art.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>