<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Visualization on Rebecca Barter</title>
    <link>/categories/visualization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Visualization on Rebecca Barter</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 23:13:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/visualization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting fancy with ggplot2: code for alternatives to grouped bar charts</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-05-29_getting_fancy_ggplot2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 23:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-05-29_getting_fancy_ggplot2/</guid>
      <description>Here I provide the code I used to create the figures from my previous post on alternatives to grouped bar charts. You are encouraged to play with them yourself!
Bars First, I load in the libraries (the data comes from the dslabs library), and convert the data to long-form for creating the grouped bar charts.
# load in libraries library(tidyverse) library(dslabs) # combine male and female success rates into single data frame success_rates &amp;lt;- rbind( # male success rates transmute(research_funding_rates, discipline, success = success_rates_men, gender = &amp;quot;Male&amp;quot;), # female success rates transmute(research_funding_rates, discipline, success = success_rates_women, gender = &amp;quot;Female&amp;quot;))  # print the data success_rates ## discipline success gender ## 1 Chemical sciences 26.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alternatives to grouped bar charts</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-05-29_alternatives_dodged_bars/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-05-29_alternatives_dodged_bars/</guid>
      <description>At some point in your life you have probably found yourself standing face-to-face with a beast known as a grouped bar chart. Perhaps it was in a research paper where the authors were trying to compare the results of several models across different datasets, or it was in a talk given by a colleague who was trying to compare the popularity of different products among distinct groups of consumers.
The first time you encountered a grouped bar chart you might have thought “what a neat way to put so much information in a single plot!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coolors: choosing color schemes</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-06-27-colors/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-06-27-colors/</guid>
      <description>Choosing a color palette for a visualization can be one of the most time consuming parts for perfectionists like me. It can be surprisingly difficult to decide on a palette that is both visually appealing and practical, but fortunately there do exist websites to help!
For example, Coolors shoots random, appealing, color palettes at you and you can swipe from one to the next with a hit of a space-bar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive visualization in R</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-04-20-interactive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-04-20-interactive/</guid>
      <description>Last week I gave an SGSA seminar on interactive visualizations in R.
Here is a long-form version of the talk.
Why be interactive? Interactivity allows the viewer to engage with your data in ways impossible by static graphs. With an interactive plot, the viewer can zoom into the areas the care about, highlight the data points that are relevant to them and hide the information that isn’t.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>